# Jesse Broxton

Email: lamarbroxton@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jesse-broxton/

Github: https://github.com/scarletknight13

Portfolio:https://warm-pavlova-f21bd7.netlify.app/

Software engineer, computer scientist, and problem solver. I have been studying and practicing computer science for the last three years and I really enjoy the science part of computer science. Proficient in C++ and Full Stack softwares and looking to use my experience and problem solving skills to create solutions that will better people's lives.

#### **Skills**

#### Technical

Javascript | Express | C ++ | Python | Game Development | Web Scraping | MongoDB | React | APIs | CSS | HTML | Node | Jquery | Database Management | Heroku | Strategic Planning | Netlify | SQL | Postgres | Django | Excel | Tableau | Asynchronous Programming

#### Soft

Teamwork | Complex Problem Solving | Time Management | Communication | Self-Driven | Adaptability

#### Education

GENERAL ASSEMBLY SOFTWARE ENGINEERING IMMERSIVE March 2022 - Present

#### Projects:

- Youtube Clone: <a href="https://dry-forest-91090.herokuapp.com/">https://dry-forest-91090.herokuapp.com/</a> A functioning clone of the popular website, Youtube. My team and I used Mongoose, Express, and Node to complete this project.
- Dots-And-Boxes: <a href="https://scarletknight13.github.io/Dots-and-Boxes/">https://scarletknight13.github.io/Dots-and-Boxes/</a> Recreation of the famous dots and boxes game. I used Vanilla JS, CSS, and HTML to create the UI. I used recursion and backtracking to create a computer AI for the 2 player mode.
- Jsudo: <a href="https://github.com/scarletknight13/JSudo">https://github.com/scarletknight13/JSudo</a> A variant of sudoku that allows the user to fill the entire board. The user gets a score based on the specific placement of numbers.
- DuoAmigo <a href="https://main--duo-amigo.netlify.app/">https://main--duo-amigo.netlify.app/</a> Me and a partner chose to make a web application that could bridge the language barrier. This app allows users to message each other and translate text between dozens of languages.

CONCORDIA UNIVERSITY CHICAGO, River Forest, IL

Relevant Courses - CS1, CS2, Discrete Structures, Data Structures

- My team won Top 10 in U.S. in the IEEExtreme 15.0 competition
- Volunteered in program that taught middle schoolers computer science
- Vice President on the IEEE club

## **Professional Experience**

#### **Store Associate**

ALDI, Bellwood, IL July 2021-Present

- Handled cash and EFT transactions quickly and accurately
- Efficiently stocked shelves to help store achieve least loss in the region.

• Excelled in a fast paced environment.

### Carpenter

DICKERSON CONSTRUCTION, Nashville TN July 2020–May 2021

- Created ways to improve structural foundation.
- Implemented practices that improved safety for team
- Worked in a crew to renovate homes.